Welcome to our video next steps for sellers who've enrolled a brand.
You've
enrolled your brand in Amazon brand registry.
Congrats!
After brand registry
approves your enrollment, both your brand registry and seller central accounts will
be associated with your brand, and you'll be ready to enjoy additional selling
benefits, added protections, and greater control over your product detail pages.
As you begin to explore all the opportunities available, make sure you
also complete a few key steps in order.
Your first step after enrollment with
brand registry should be listing your products.
If you haven't already listed
your brand's products in the Amazon store, wait until after you've received
confirmation that your enrollment is approved.
After approval, you can list
using our standard processes.
You'll be able to use the brand name field to
select or enter your registered brand name.
If you enter your brand name
manually, make sure it matches the name on your trademark exactly.
This helps
ensure that your products are associated with your brand and integrated into the
tools reserved for enrolled brands.
To get step-by-step instructions for the
full listing process, see the series of modules in our list products course in
Seller University.
If you previously listed products within your brand by
entering an unregistered brand name in the brand name field, you should contact
Seller Support after your enrollment in brand registry is approved.
Tell them that
you want to sync your existing listings with your newly registered brand name
and provide the name of your brand as it appears on your trademark as well as a
list of relevant ASINs.
You should do this even if the name in the brand name
field isn't changing so that your existing products can be associated with
your brand's registration.
If you previously listed your brand's products
in the Amazon store by entering or selecting generic in the brand name
field, you should delete those listings and create new ones using your newly
registered brand name.
We can't associate an existing listing with a
registered brand after generic has been used as a brand name value.
After your
products are listed and associated with your brand, you can activate each brand
benefit for your selling account.
You can find them all by hovering over the
Brands section of the main menu in Seller Central clicking build your brand
and scrolling down to the bottom of the page.
There's no exact order for
activating selling benefits.
Some brands configure settings for the subscribe and
save program then use brand analytics dashboards to understand the impact.
Others review brand analytics dashboards first then decide to group and sell
their products as virtual bundles.
But it's important to note that some
benefits are designed to be activated ahead of others.
For example, a brand
needs to create a store before they can use posts to attract followers.
They also
need a store before they can create sponsored brands campaigns because those
campaigns include a link to their store.
In general, we recommend starting with
selling benefits that can help grow the audience for your brand like A+ content
and stores.
Then we recommend investing in programs like subscribe and save and
virtual bundles which can generate repeat purchases and other types of
customer loyalty.
When you've optimized your brand's Amazon footprint and
operations, we recommend informing your strategy with tools like Manage Your Experiments and brand
analytics.
It's also never a bad time to reinvest in
protections for your brand.
If you qualify for programs like Transparency or
Project Zero, enrolling in them can help keep you and your customers safe from
counterfeits and other types of IP infringement.
And every enrolled brand can
use the report a violation tool at any time to notify Amazon of suspected IP
violations.
As you use various brand benefits, you can also reach out to seller
support if you ever suspect that one of your products hasn't been successfully
associated with your enrolled brand.
For example, if a product appears to be
missing from a brand analytics dashboard, provide seller support with the exact
brand name that appears on your trademark along with the ASIN that you
think may not yet be associated.
Another step you may want to take after
enrolling your brand is connecting it to additional seller central or brand
registry accounts.
By doing so, you can provide additional Amazon sellers with
listing privileges for the brand, meaning they can create or suggest updates to
your brand's product detail pages.
These additional sellers are eligible to
activate brand selling benefits too.
Through separate processes, you can also
assign one or more roles to additional brand registry accounts, which gives
them access to various permission settings and protection tools.
For more
information about associating additional seller central accounts with your brand,
see our seller university video "Manage Selling Benefits for Your Brand" and to
learn more about affiliating additional brand registry accounts, see our video
"
Manage Amazon Brand Registry Roles".
This concludes our training.
Thank you and
happy selling in the Amazon store.